<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Models on ARCHIMED user documentation</title>
    <link>/3-inputs/5-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Models on ARCHIMED user documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/3-inputs/5-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple model file</title>
      <link>/3-inputs/5-models/1-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3-inputs/5-models/1-models/</guid>
      <description>In ARCHIMED-φ, an object is defined by:
- its geometry, read from an .opf or a .gwa file;
- (optionally) its topology and the types of components used to build it, only read from an .opf file;
- its functional group, read from an .ops file.
The geometry (and topology) of an object is built using components (see the opf documentation). For example a simple coffee tree can be built using two components: leaves and internodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of the models</title>
      <link>/3-inputs/5-models/2-models_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3-inputs/5-models/2-models_list/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of all models available for each process.
Interception There are three different models available in ARCHIMED-φ to compute their light interception and scattering: Translucent, ignore and VirtualSensor.
Translucent This model has two set of parameters :
 transparency: between 0 and 1. 0 is not transparent (opaque), and 1 fully transparent. If it is set to e.g. 0.3, 70% of the incoming light is intercepted by the component (interception = radiation * (1-transparency)), and 30% is directly transmitted (not being part of the interception).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soil model</title>
      <link>/3-inputs/5-models/3-soil_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3-inputs/5-models/3-soil_model/</guid>
      <description>The soil file is the same as any plant file so far (e.g. group, type, model parameters), but will be populated with new parameters soon. It is identified as a soil file if it uses the Cobblestone component type:
--- Group: pavement Type: Cobblestone: Interception: model: Translucent transparency: 0 optical_properties: PAR: 0.15 NIR: 0.9 plot_paving: 80 ...  The Cobblestone type is a special type that defines a soil as a plane, discretized in cobblestones for the light interception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual sensor</title>
      <link>/3-inputs/5-models/4-virtual_sensors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3-inputs/5-models/4-virtual_sensors/</guid>
      <description>More information on how to use virtual sensors soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>