<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3D scene on ARCHIMED user documentation</title>
    <link>/3-inputs/4-scene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3D scene on ARCHIMED user documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/3-inputs/4-scene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scene file</title>
      <link>/3-inputs/4-scene/1-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3-inputs/4-scene/1-ops/</guid>
      <description>.ops The .ops file defines a 3D scene compatible with ARCHIMED-φ and AMAPStudio. The file is used to define a scene, and place 3D objects inside. The .ops file used in ARCHIMED-φ is a subset of the .ops file from AMAPStudio, meaning they don’t implement all the features (e.g. chaining).
Example Here is the content of an example file for a scene with two coffee trees:
# T xOrigin yOrigin zOrigin xSize ySize flat T 0 0 0 2 2 flat #[Archimed] coffee #sceneId objectId FilePath x y z scale inclinationAzimut inclinationAngle rotation 1 1 opf/P6_Ru_ii_L2P02.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant file</title>
      <link>/3-inputs/4-scene/2-opf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3-inputs/4-scene/2-opf/</guid>
      <description>.opf The .opf file extension stands for Open Plant Format. It allows to store the topology, the geometry and any other attribute of a plant. The format is heavily inspired by the MTG format (Multi-scale Tree Graph) for the topology representation.
The file is encoded in the XML format, so many editors can render its structure. The .opf file describes vertices, faces, normals, texture coordinates, materials (colors), attributes and transformation matrices for the geometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geometry file</title>
      <link>/3-inputs/4-scene/3-gwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:15:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3-inputs/4-scene/3-gwa/</guid>
      <description>.gwa The .gwa files are used to represent any geometrical object. It is based on the same format than the .opf (and is an XML too), but without the topology.
A simple example of a virtual table is available here:
  Attachments   table.gwa  (12 kb)    And here is a 3d render of this file:
 A simple table by rvezy on Sketchfab  If you open the file, you’ll see several sections.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>